Register of the Petr Arkad'evich Stolypin subject collection, 1933-1952
Hoover Institution Archives
Petr Arkad'evich Stolypin Subject Collection,
1933-1952
2000C25
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Letters, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to the Russian statesman Petr Stolypin.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Stolypin, Petr Arkad'evich, 1862-1911.; Russia--Politics and government--1894-1917.; Russia.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of clippings, correspondence and other biographical material collected by the staff of the Museum of Russian Culture relating to the life and career of P. A. Stolypin, as well as to his family. The correspondence is between the director of the Museum, P. F. Konstantinov, and Stolypin's son, Arkadii.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Series Description
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1951-1952, Box 1
  Correspondence between Arkadii P. Stolypin and Petr F. Konstantinov, arranged chronologically
- PRINTED MATTER, 1933-1951, Box 1
  Clippings, brochures, newspaper issues relating to Stolypin
- MISCELLANY, 1936-1951, Box 1
  Speeches in honor of Stolypin, his genealogy and memorable quotes
Container List
- Correspondence, 1951-1952
  - Letters from Arkadii Petrovich Stolypin to Petr Filaretovich Konstantinov, mainly concerning the establishment of a Stolypin display in the Museum of Russian Culture (Box 1: 1, Folder 1)
- Printed Matter, 1933-1951
  - Newspaper clippings and issues and other printed matter relating to the life and career of P. A. Stolypin (Box 1: 2-7)
- Miscellany, 1936-1951
  - Speeches
    - Budberg, A. P. Includes postcard from D. B. Neidgardt, [1936]-1937 (Box 1: 8)
    - Vagin, A. N. Includes correspondence related to commemorations of Stolypin in San Francisco in 1936 and 1951 (Box 1: 9)
  - Stolypin's genealogy and memorable quotes (Box 1: 10)